<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
      <channel>
        <title>centsai</title>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <description>centsai</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 09:08:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <updatePeriod>hourly</updatePeriod>
        <updateFrequency type="integer">1</updateFrequency>
        <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
        <item>
              <title>Extreme Debt Payoff: Turning to Prostitution to Pay Medical Bills</title>
              <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 09:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
              <guid>3280</guid>
              <content>"\u003c!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC \"-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN\" \"http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd\"\u003e\n\u003c?xml encoding=\"utf-8\" ?\u003e\u003chtml\u003e\u003cbody\u003e\u003cp\u003eThe total cost of Cassandra\u0026rsquo;s mother\u0026rsquo;s heart bypass surgery after her second heart attack was $104,398.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eIn the United States, rising health care costs mean that Americans spend over $3.8 trillion per year on medical expenses, according to the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services. For many Americans, this can mean lifelong expenses that can burden generations of family members.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eHer mother\u0026rsquo;s first surgery had already resulted in Cassandra* losing her job as a secretary for a real estate company. After the second operation, with no job, no insurance, no spouse, and nowhere to turn, Cassandra\u0026rsquo;s mother asked her daughter, a recent grad working as a marketing analyst, for help.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eBut Cassandra didn\u0026rsquo;t have that kind of money. She couldn\u0026rsquo;t even afford to pay her student loans or to live in her own apartment.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eStill, Cassandra wanted to help. Her mom had raised her without any financial support and had struggled to ensure that she could pursue her dream of getting into one of the top universities in the country.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eShe couldn\u0026rsquo;t sit idly by while bill collectors hounded her mother during such a critical time.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u0026ldquo;What kind of daughter would I be?\u0026rdquo; Cassandra says. \u0026ldquo;What kind of human would I be? I had to do something. If she knew what I had to do to pay off those bills, I think she would never forgive me.\u0026rdquo;\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eFor Cassandra, paying down $104,000 meant restarting her life by beginning her own business as a prostitute \u0026mdash; a job that could have landed her in prison \u0026mdash; or gotten her killed.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eNo Other Way to Pay the Bills\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eCassandra shared her worries with a few friends. One mentioned knowing someone who worked as an escort in New York, who claimed that she made around $40,000 in three months. Cassandra reached out, and the escort explained how they ran their business, how to find clients, and how to handle security and health issues.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eCassandra tentatively began developing the business end. She bought a website domain and paid for web hosting. Then she uploaded tasteful pictures of herself, along with a bio describing how she enjoyed art museums, trips overseas, and shopping at Tiffany\u0026rsquo;s.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u0026ldquo;It all felt normal,\u0026rdquo; she recalls. \u0026ldquo;It was like putting up an online dating profile.\u0026rdquo;\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eTwo weeks later, her life as a prostitute had begun. She got her first call.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u0026ldquo;It was a thrill,\u0026rdquo; she says. \u0026ldquo;I emailed him a copy of a contract I found online, and then I had him PayPal me a $1,000 deposit. He sent everything back within minutes, including an additional $500 for an extra hour.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cblockquote\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cstrong\u003e\u003cem\u003e\u0026ldquo;That night, we went to one of the top restaurants in NYC and saw a Broadway show. It was so exciting! I felt like a princess \u0026mdash; until we got back to the hotel and the real \u0026lsquo;job\u0026rsquo; began.\u0026rdquo;\u003c/em\u003e\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/blockquote\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eWhen she went home to her mother\u0026rsquo;s place, she counted her money: a total of $6,500 for six hours. Cassandra called a collector and paid off the first chunk of what was owed to the hospital\u0026rsquo;s collection services, and then she went out and filled her mother\u0026rsquo;s pantry with healthy foods.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u0026ldquo;Making that payment was the only thing I could do to keep myself from running out of my skin,\u0026rdquo; she explains.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u0026ldquo;I didn\u0026rsquo;t sleep well for months after that. But I constantly reminded myself that it was temporary, a means to an end for both my mother and me.\u0026rdquo;\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan class=\"aff-cta\"\u003e\u003clabel\u003eOpen a Health Savings Account to Lower Your Out of Pocket Medical Costs\u003c/label\u003e Lively Health Savings Accounts are 100% Fee-Free\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cdiv class=\"chck-lst-box small-box\"\u003e\r\n\t\t\t\u003cdiv class=\"chck-lst-head\"\u003e\u003cspan\u003eOther Ways to Repay Medical Debt\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/div\u003e\r\n            \u003cdiv class=\"chck-lst-body\"\u003e\u003cp\u003eFortunately, turning to prostitution is not the only way to relieve your debt. There are many ways to satisfy collections agencies without having to use methods you may not want to pursue. Here are some tips from a bankruptcy and debt relief attorney at the Luftman, Heck, and Associates LLP, Matthew Alden.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003col\u003e\u003cli\u003e\u003cstrong\u003ePursue the Debt Settlement Option: \u003c/strong\u003eBy having a lawyer negotiate a lower balance with a medical provider, you can avoid having to pay the full balance, which can save you tens of thousands, if not more, in the long run.\u003c/li\u003e\n\u003cli\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eHire a Debt Relief Lawyer:\u003c/strong\u003e If you\u0026rsquo;re injured and unable to pay the medical debt, hire a debt relief lawyer to reach an agreement with the medical provider called contingency medical payments. As a result, they cannot bill you or send the bill to collections, until you have received your settlement.\u003c/li\u003e\n\u003cli\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eFile for \u003c/strong\u003eChapter 13 Bankruptcy\u003cstrong\u003e: \u003c/strong\u003eThis is not the most popular option, but it will help you eliminate extreme medical debt utilizing a three to five year repayment plan.\u003c/li\u003e\n\u003c/ol\u003e\u003c/div\u003e\r\n          \u003c/div\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cstrong\u003ePaying off the Debt\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eIn her first year in the life of a prostitute, Cassandra picked up six regular clients, which allowed her to pay off nearly $75,000 of her mom\u0026rsquo;s debt. Part of her income also went to keeping herself healthy and safe.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eAfter a close call one night with a potentially dangerous new client, she began running comprehensive background checks and hired a security guard to join her at the start and end of each date.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eShe also paid for weekly visits to the doctor and an independent health insurance plan for herself and her mother. All of those business expenses accounted for nearly $25,000 annually.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u0026ldquo;I really loved the idea that I was running my own business,\u0026rdquo; she says. \u0026ldquo;I started to learn things I never knew how to do in college, like accounting and payroll\u0026hellip;But I still wanted nothing more than to close it down.\u0026rdquo;\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cblockquote\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cstrong\u003e\u003cem\u003eCassandra\u0026rsquo;s mom, who took about nine months to fully recover, never really questioned what was happening to the bills.\u003c/em\u003e\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/blockquote\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eWhen the phone calls stopped coming, Cassandra told her mother that she had decided to go back to school and use the student loans to pay the monthly payments. She also disguised her life as a prostitute as part of a new job at a startup marketing company.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eMeanwhile, Cassandra confided in her regular clients about the situation \u0026mdash; and was surprised at their reaction.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u0026ldquo;They stopped buying me designer clothes,\u0026rdquo; she recalls, \u0026ldquo;and instead gave me gift cards to grocery stores and gas stations, so I could get my mom to a doctor.\u0026rdquo;\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eOne of her clients even offered to pay off all the debt in exchange for a weeklong overseas trip. She accepted, and after nearly 20 months, Cassandra\u0026rsquo;s call girl service ended with one trip to Japan.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eThe Worth of Selling Yourself\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eThe year after she stopped her business, Cassandra enrolled in an MBA program where she studied nonprofits and found a job as a marketing analyst for a major nonprofit. Her mother made a full recovery and now lives with Cassandra and her new husband.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eCassandra says she has many regrets. \u0026ldquo;Every day was a regret,\u0026rdquo; she says. \u0026ldquo;I don\u0026rsquo;t like what I did, even if it was for the right reasons.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u0026ldquo;Now, I wish I had taken over the debt sooner, gotten a payment plan set up, or maybe even worked with a financial advisor on how I could have solved this without becoming a call girl. I was young and stupid. But it worked out in the end, and I can\u0026rsquo;t pretend like my life wouldn\u0026rsquo;t be this great or debt-free if I hadn\u0026rsquo;t done what I did.\u0026rdquo;\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cem\u003e*Name has been changed to protect privacy.\u003c/em\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/body\u003e\u003c/html\u003e\n"</content>
              <cc></cc>
              <media><url></url></media>
            </item>\n<item>
              <title>Investing in Real Estate</title>
              <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 09:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
              <guid>80175</guid>
              <content>"\u003c!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC \"-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN\" \"http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd\"\u003e\n\u003c?xml encoding=\"utf-8\" ?\u003e\u003chtml\u003e\u003cbody\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eThe second best performing asset class is overlooked by many investors. In the long term, real estate has performed second only to stocks as a broad asset class. Yet few investors hold sufficient real estate positions in their portfolios.\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eInvestors, in general, know they need to include investments in both stocks and bonds to have a diversified portfolio. What they may not know is that adherence to a strict stock and bond model is likely hurting their long-term results.\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cb\u003eWhy Real Estate\u003c/b\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eInvestors can invest into real estate as an equity investment or as a debt investment. Though both have merits, the equity side of real estate can help drive portfolio returns while simultaneously reducing portfolio level volatility. Many investors are over investing in bonds, to the detriment of their retirements or other goals.\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eBonds can help stabilize a portfolio, reducing volatility and making investors more comfortable with their portfolio\u0026rsquo;s performance. But bonds are not a great place to be at the moment, and haven\u0026rsquo;t really been so for a long time.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eInvestors are trading away their portfolio\u0026rsquo;s long-term gains so they can have some more predictable day-to-day returns. That is really all they are achieving with their over concentrations of bond investments in long-term portfolios.\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cblockquote\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eBecause\u0026nbsp; many investors are or may be underfunding their retirements, subpar returns are something they can ill afford.\u003c/strong\u003e \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/blockquote\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eThere are two things investors need to be very cognizant of in building toward long-term goals. One is their gross level of return, even small differences in returns compound across time. This is the primary reason for so much advice to minimize fees \u0026mdash; they erode returns across time, leaving investors far less to use for their goals.\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eThe second thing is the deleterious effect of inflation. Inflation erodes real rates of return by reducing the purchasing power of future dollars. Portfolios need to not only outpace the current rate of inflation, but also hedge against a run-up in inflation. We have been in a benign inflation environment for many years, but that can change at any time.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eReal estate correlates positively with inflation. Real estate prices move up with other prices, providing a degree of hedge against inflation.\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cb\u003eHow to Invest in Real Estate\u003c/b\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eThere are a number of ways investors can invest into real estate. They have options to do so directly, or they can pool with other investors. Here are some of the main options available to investors.\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cb\u003eRental\u003c/b\u003e \u003cb\u003eReal\u003c/b\u003e \u003cb\u003eEstate:\u003c/b\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e Investors can purchase one or more properties and rent them out. This approach is certainly not for everyone. It gives you a lot of control over what you own, but comes with a lot of work and a lot of potential headaches. \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eNot everyone is cut out to deal with problem tenants. Owning real estate and renting it out can be a great way to make money, if you are willing and able to do the work. For most investors, this approach involves too much time and too much risk.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cb\u003eHouse\u003c/b\u003e \u003cb\u003eFlipping:\u003c/b\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e There are many television shows showing professional house flippers making \u0026ldquo;easy money\u0026rdquo; flipping houses. There is no easy money in house flipping; there is a lot of work and a lot of risk. \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eSome people can make money house flipping, but far more people probably can\u0026rsquo;t. For most investors, this would be a worse idea than rental real estate.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cb\u003eCrowdfunding\u003c/b\u003e \u003cb\u003eOptions:\u003c/b\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e The number of things we cannot do online continues to dwindle. Investors can invest into real estate investments through several online platforms, similar to crowdfunding. \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cblockquote\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eThe more serious of these require accreditation or have other barriers to entry, limiting their applicability for the average investor.\u003c/strong\u003e \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/blockquote\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eAlso notable for the average investor is the lack of liquidity in crowdsourced investments, limiting their practicality for smaller investors.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cb\u003eReal Estate Investment Trusts:\u003c/b\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e Real estate investment trusts (REITs)\u003c/span\u003e \u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003epool investors together to fund the purchase and/or development of real estate projects.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eMany focus on particular sectors, and hence there are different risk characteristics depending on the underlying investments and other factors. REITs can either be publicly traded on exchanges or private placement through brokers. \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eBoth can offer investors a great way to get into real estate without the headaches of direct ownership and with somewhat lower risk characteristics. Investors can further limit their risk by investing into different types of REITs.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cb\u003eExchange Traded Funds: \u003c/b\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eInvestors can invest in a variety of real estate investments through Exchange Traded Funds (ETFs).\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eETFs offer investors the chance to invest into real estate through indexes or a variety of other options, which provides investors with the upside of real estate without the liquidity problems of many other real estate options.\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cb\u003eAdditional Considerations\u003c/b\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eThere is no magic bullet for portfolio construction. But ignoring a strong performing asset class that can reduce overall volatility while providing a hedge against inflation would be a mistake.\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eThere is not a single risk profile for real estate investments, as there are many types of real estate and many ways to invest into real estate. \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cblockquote\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eInvestors need to do their due diligence to make sure they understand what they are getting into and what the risks associated with the investment are.\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/blockquote\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eOne large factor in the performance and risk or real estate investments is leverage. Some real estate portfolios are constructed on an all-cash basis; others use a degree of leverage by borrowing money for a portion of the funding. \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eUsing leverage increases an investor\u0026rsquo;s potential return, while simultaneously increasing risk. There isn\u0026rsquo;t a right or wrong way; it is just a factor that the investor should be aware of. Leverage can be a wonderful tool if understood and used correctly. But no risk should be undertaken without understanding any potential consequences.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eRisk is always a double-edged sword. Many investors focus on minimizing volatility without giving adequate consideration to how much potential return they are sacrificing for that perceived advantage. \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eBy minimizing their short-term risk, they are unknowingly increasing the risk of not achieving their goals. In the end, what you have accumulated is what will enable you to achieve your goals. \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eReal estate investments deserve consideration for any long-term portfolio. They\u0026rsquo;re not a silver bullet, but they can help a lot of too conservatively structured long-term portfolios.\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/body\u003e\u003c/html\u003e\n"</content>
              <cc></cc>
              <media><url></url></media>
            </item>\n<item>
              <title>Setting New Financial Goals After Paying Off Debt</title>
              <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 09:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
              <guid>3323</guid>
              <content>"\u003c!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC \"-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN\" \"http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd\"\u003e\n\u003c?xml encoding=\"utf-8\" ?\u003e\u003chtml\u003e\u003cbody\u003e\u003cp\u003eAt the time of writing, I am witnessing the beginning of my life after debt. This is the first month of my adult life that I don\u0026rsquo;t owe anyone money. I was paying off student loans for nine years, and I\u0026rsquo;ve never known what it\u0026rsquo;s like to \u003cem\u003enot\u003c/em\u003e be in debt\u0026hellip;until now.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eOne December, I made the last payment on my student loans. Though I\u0026rsquo;m debt-free now, I\u0026rsquo;m starting at ground zero. It\u0026rsquo;s a new beginning for me in many ways \u0026mdash; a fresh start, a time to rebuild.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003eGetting Out of Debt\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eTo get out of debt, I had to tap into my emergency fund. Currently, it sits at an uncomfortable level \u0026mdash; an amount that would hardly help in a real emergency. I have approximately $600 in a Roth IRA \u0026hellip; and that\u0026rsquo;s it.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cblockquote\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eI\u0026rsquo;m in my 30s, but my finances feel young and immature. \u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/blockquote\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eI need to catch up to where I should be financially, and save for my future and personal goals. This year, I have big plans to start over and finally have my money work for me. I plan to:\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cul\u003e\u003cli\u003eFully fund my emergency fund ($10,000)\u003c/li\u003e\n\u003cli\u003eInvest $20,000 in index funds and my Roth IRA.\u003c/li\u003e\n\u003c/ul\u003e\u003cp\u003eThese goals are ambitious, to say the least, but I am hopeful and determined. Last year, I put $30,000 toward debt, so theoretically, I could put that same amount toward saving and investing.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eThere\u0026rsquo;s just one problem: I\u0026rsquo;m moving to a location with a higher cost of living.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eWhile paying off debt, I\u0026rsquo;ve remained in Portland, Oregon, where my expenses are low. The catch? I\u0026rsquo;m not happy here. After four years of trying to be happy, it finally makes sense to move somewhere else now that I\u0026rsquo;ve entered my life after debt.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eI\u0026rsquo;m moving to Los Angeles, where I am from, and where my parents live. I expect my rent to double when I move. It will be a challenge to pay double my rent and also save and invest $30,000. But there are ways that I plan to accomplish my goals:\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch3\u003e\u003cstrong\u003e1. Earning More\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h3\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eThis year, I plan to earn more by targeting high-paying clients, asking for raises, and selling stuff before the move. In addition, I plan to diversify my income streams even further.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch3\u003e\u003cstrong\u003e2. Automated Savings\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h3\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eI\u0026rsquo;m a huge fan of automation when it comes to finances. As humans, we make a lot of excuses for why we don\u0026rsquo;t do things. I\u0026rsquo;m no different. I\u0026rsquo;ve found that paying myself first through automatic contributions is the best policy. I automatically save 10 percent of my income, but I plan to increase that to at least 25 percent and contribute more as I can.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch3\u003e\u003cstrong\u003e3. Avoiding Lifestyle Inflation\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h3\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eEven though I\u0026rsquo;m debt-free now, I plan on keeping the lifestyle I have, for the most part. I don\u0026rsquo;t plan on suddenly increasing my expenses (aside from rent).\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan class=\"aff-cta\"\u003ePay Down Debt Faster With an Automated Debt Management App Get Started\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eI don\u0026rsquo;t have a car, a pet, cable, a gym membership, and I don\u0026rsquo;t buy clothes unless I have to \u0026mdash; and I plan to keep it that way. Although my goals are ambitious, and to be honest it feels a bit stressful, I\u0026rsquo;m ready to finally live life on my terms, and not in the shadow of debt.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eI\u0026rsquo;m going to make my money work for me and use it as a tool to be happy and enjoy life, no longer being crushed by the burden of debt.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eIn 2021, my goals are to grow my podcast, The Mental Health and Wealth show, focus on creating digital products to make passive income, and continue investing in index funds to multiple six figures.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eSetting Financial Goals\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eYou may be asking yourself what to do after you\u0026rsquo;ve reached the life after debt. \u0026ldquo;Paying off debt is like getting past the doorman. Now as a debt-free person you have more room and space to enjoy your hard-earned money,\u0026rdquo; states Jacent Wamala, licensed marriage and family therapist and money mindset coach.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u0026ldquo;You have to transition into a new frame of mind and budgeting in a whole new way,\u0026rdquo; Wamala adds. \u0026ldquo;Include a line item in your budget to allow for fun money to be spent in the areas you value. Address your scarcity mindset that keeps you feeling restricted.\u0026rdquo;\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eYou may also be asking yourself what the plan should be in the months following such a big milestone. \u0026ldquo;The next thing to do is to actually set another goal,\u0026rdquo; asserts Paul Sundin, CPA and tax strategist at Emparion. \u0026ldquo;When it comes to financial matters, the goals are endless, just like numbers are almost endless.\u0026rdquo;\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cblockquote\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eGiving yourself something else to work toward can help you stay focused.\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/blockquote\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eWhether it\u0026rsquo;s paying off student loan debt, saving a certain amount in an emergency fund, or starting a retirement account, here are some tips to help you on your next goal:\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cul\u003e\u003cli\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eRethink Your \u003c/strong\u003eBudget\u003cstrong\u003e:\u003c/strong\u003e Examine your priorities and long-term financial goals now that your burden of debt has been removed. \u0026ldquo;It is important not to feel deprived when you are building out your new budget, because people then tend to rebel against it. By setting realistic budgets and goals you will set yourself up for success,\u0026rdquo; says Erika Wasserman, a financial therapist.\u003c/li\u003e\n\u003cli\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eRebuild Your \u003c/strong\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eEmergency Fund\u003c/strong\u003e\u003cstrong\u003e:\u003c/strong\u003e Having an emergency fund is still important even if you have reached your financial goals. If this was your goal, great! See if you can pad it even more.\u003c/li\u003e\n\u003cli\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eIncrease Your \u003c/strong\u003eRetirement Fund\u003cstrong\u003e Contribution:\u003c/strong\u003e Now is the time to add and add a lot to your retirement so you are well prepared later in life.\u003c/li\u003e\n\u003cli\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eBegin to \u003c/strong\u003eInvest\u003cstrong\u003e:\u003c/strong\u003e Being debt-free now gives you the ability to take risks with your money \u0026#12540; and possibly earn rewards.\u003c/li\u003e\n\u003c/ul\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/body\u003e\u003c/html\u003e\n"</content>
              <cc></cc>
              <media><url></url></media>
            </item>\n<item>
              <title>How to Close the Gender Wage Gap: 4 Tips for Women</title>
              <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 09:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
              <guid>22194</guid>
              <content>"\u003c!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC \"-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN\" \"http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd\"\u003e\n\u003c?xml encoding=\"utf-8\" ?\u003e\u003chtml\u003e\u003cbody\u003e\u003cp\u003eWomen are earning more than they used to, getting married later, and generally living life on their own terms \u0026mdash; with or without a partner. But despite all that progress, women still earn less than men, even when they do the same kinds of work. This is known as the gender wage gap.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eWhat Is the Gender Wage Gap?\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eThe median salary for women is about 22 percent lower than that for men, according to data from Payscale. That translates to women receiving, on average, 81 cents for every dollar that men make. Though that wage gap may not seem big, it equates to thousands of dollars over a woman\u0026rsquo;s lifetime.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eHistorically, this has always been a problem. During World War I, women went on strike in the U.K. when they realized they were expected to perform the exact same work as their male counterparts for less pay.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eAs women\u0026rsquo;s suffrage was still that could be leveraged, women\u0026rsquo;s groups and trade unions began to mobilize and demand equal pay and unemployment benefits as part of an election issue. The issue was raised again during World War II and finding solutions to the gender wage gap became an increasingly common demand by unions and women\u0026rsquo;s groups in the 1950s.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eIn the last few decades, the wage gap has narrowed slightly, but not by nearly enough, according to a report by Pew Research Center. If you take a look at the most recent data from the U.S. Census Bureau, despite the fact that both men and women have seen overall wages increase, men still earn more \u0026mdash; by more than $10,000 on average.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cimg loading=\"lazy\" class=\"wp-image-53217 size-full aligncenter\" src=\"https://centsai.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Gender-wage-gap-US-Census-Bureau-Chart.png\" alt=\"How to Close the Gender Wage Gap: 4 Tips for Women | Gender Wage Gap Chart\" width=\"1600\" height=\"1119\" srcset=\"https://centsai.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Gender-wage-gap-US-Census-Bureau-Chart.png 1600w, https://centsai.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Gender-wage-gap-US-Census-Bureau-Chart.png 463w, https://centsai.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Gender-wage-gap-US-Census-Bureau-Chart.png 794w\" sizes=\"(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px\"\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eYes, it sucks that we\u0026rsquo;re still waiting for legislation to level the playing field and that we have to do this on our own, but women need to take action to help find solutions to the gender wage gap. Here\u0026rsquo;s how:\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch3\u003e\u003cstrong\u003e1. Keep Calm and Do Your Homework\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h3\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eYou should always have a starting reference point for how much you\u0026rsquo;re worth. Though the exact numbers can be a little fuzzy, typical pay depends a lot on the job\u0026rsquo;s title, responsibilities, experience, and location. A salesperson in the Midwest won\u0026rsquo;t earn the same salary as a salesperson in New York City or San Francisco.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u0026ldquo;It is important to research your industry and get an idea of what your male counterparts are being paid. Glassdoor is a great place to glean some insight into what others are making,\u0026rdquo; says career and business expert Heather Monahan.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch3\u003e\u003cstrong\u003e2. Negotiate (Even When It\u0026rsquo;s Uncomfortable)\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h3\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cimg loading=\"lazy\" class=\"alignleft size-medium wp-image-54115\" src=\"https://centsai.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/How-You-Can-Help-Close-the-Gender-Pay-Gap-Now.png\" alt=\"How You Can Help Close the Gender Pay Gap Now. Pay differences still affect many women. Don't wait for legislation to catch up with the times. Learn how to close the #genderwagegap today. #GenderWage #GenderWageGapMyth #GenderGap #Gendergapmenandwomen\" width=\"338\" height=\"579\" srcset=\"https://centsai.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/How-You-Can-Help-Close-the-Gender-Pay-Gap-Now.png 338w, https://centsai.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/How-You-Can-Help-Close-the-Gender-Pay-Gap-Now.png 324w, https://centsai.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/How-You-Can-Help-Close-the-Gender-Pay-Gap-Now.png 735w\" sizes=\"(max-width: 338px) 100vw, 338px\"\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eThere are countless studies that show that women are less likely than men to negotiate their salary.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eShamefully, I\u0026rsquo;m one of them. I held a traditional nine-to-five job for nearly a decade, and yet I never once attempted to negotiate my salary. Why? Because I thought I was \u0026ldquo;lucky\u0026rdquo; to have a job at all after the Great Recession.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eI didn\u0026rsquo;t want to appear greedy, overconfident, or as if I took my job for granted. During those years, I lost out on a lot of money because I chose to play it safe.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eWhat many may be unaware of, however, is that women are as likely as men to negotiate pay when the opportunity arises, according to a study by Industrial Relations: A Journal of Economy and Society.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eThis means that we have been taught to accept what we have. We could see a certain level of progress if we remind ourselves and our female co-workers that there may be more opportunities for negotiation than we realize.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan class=\"aff-cta\"\u003e\u003clabel\u003eSign Up for an Investing Service That Empowers Women\u003c/label\u003e Get Started\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eIt is worth your time. Not only will you earn more, but you\u0026rsquo;ll also gain more respect from your employers.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cblockquote\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cstrong\u003e\u003cem\u003e\u0026ldquo;Oftentimes a woman will decide why a company can\u0026rsquo;t give her a raise before ever asking,\u0026rdquo; Monahan says.\u003c/em\u003e\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/blockquote\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eI can attest to this. I worked in the nonprofit sector \u0026mdash; a notoriously low-paying field \u0026mdash; so I just assumed I could never ask for more money. But even if I couldn\u0026rsquo;t earn more monetarily, I could have still negotiated for something else.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u0026ldquo;Always ask for more in anticipation of negotiating,\u0026rdquo; says Monahan. \u0026ldquo;Remember that when you give up something in a negotiation, you need to get something back in return.\u0026rdquo;\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eIn other words, even if you don\u0026rsquo;t get the boost in salary that you want, you can negotiate benefits. Ask for more time off, work-from-home days, or another perk of your choice. You name it!\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch3\u003e\u003cstrong\u003e3. Boost Your Confidence (Even If You Have to Fake It)\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h3\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eConfidence can help you ask for what you want without wavering. It\u0026rsquo;s hard to muster up, but you can do it. The second step to finding a solution to the gender wage gap is to find your confidence. The first is believing. One unique source of inspiration? Donald Trump.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u0026ldquo;Since Donald Trump took office, I have watched how his high level of confidence and clarity in each of his steps \u0026mdash; whether justified or not \u0026mdash; has gotten him to where he is today,\u0026rdquo; Monahan says. \u0026ldquo;Typically, women do not move forward with brash confidence and an attitude of daring others to challenge them. What would happen if we did?\u0026rdquo;\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eNow, the former president may not be so inspiring to everyone, but Monahan encourages women to look up to people who have a similar level of confidence.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch3\u003e\u003cstrong\u003e4. Invest, Invest, Invest\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h3\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eMost women are good at taking care of everyone but themselves. Women tend to live longer than our male counterparts (an average man will live to 84.3, and women will live to 86.7), yet we don\u0026rsquo;t invest as much as men. It\u0026rsquo;s crucial for women to invest for the long term and let their money work as hard as they do.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cblockquote\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cstrong\u003e\u003cem\u003eWomen will always be behind if they don\u0026rsquo;t use time to their advantage.\u003c/em\u003e\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/blockquote\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eCash investments represent a larger portion for women investors at 68 percent compared with male investors at 59 percent.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eSo commit to investing today, and let your money work for you and earn higher returns. Building wealth can help you create financial freedom, a sufficient nest egg, and more opportunities. Investing can seem scary, but it\u0026rsquo;s a smart move in the long term.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eYou can also use the Social Security Administration\u0026rsquo;s life expectancy calculator to plan how to make your money work for you over the course of your life and invest wisely.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eWhat Women Should Consider Financially as They Age\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003ch3\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eIn Your 20s\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h3\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eBegin saving for your future, work hard to pay off student loans, build credit, avoid debt, take advantage of tax-protected retirement accounts, and start investing.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch3\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eIn Your 30s\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h3\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eEnsure your retirement contributions align with your goals, begin saving for your children\u0026rsquo;s education (if that\u0026rsquo;s where your future is leading), and think about buying a home.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch3\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eIn Your 40s\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h3\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eBe smart about spending and saving, ramp up retirement plan contributions, and talk to your parents about elder care. Hopefully your kids, if you have any, have part-time jobs already!\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch3\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eIn Your 50s\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h3\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eMake sure your investment portfolio is geared toward preserving wealth instead of growth, work with a financial planner to calculate needs and goals, and prioritize saving for your own retirement over saving for your children\u0026rsquo;s education.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch3\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eIn Your 60s\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h3\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eRebalance your portfolio regularly, carefully consider your Social Security distribution plan, and consider continuing to work part time as a consultant or launching your own business.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch3\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eIn Your 70s+\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h3\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eEnjoy your retirement, but continue to watch your portfolio (maybe with a financial adviser), managing risk to ensure your money doesn\u0026rsquo;t run out.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eThe Bottom Line \u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003eWomen can take actionable steps toward finding solutions for the gender wage gap. Yes, there are certain factors outside of our control, and yes, we need the rest of the world to get on board. But in the meantime, use these steps to earn more and create your own financial freedom plan.\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cstrong\u003e\u003cem\u003eAdditional reporting by Jazmin Rosa.\u003c/em\u003e\u003c/strong\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan class=\"aff-cta\"\u003e\u003clabel\u003eSign Up for an Investing Service That Empowers Women\u003c/label\u003e Get Started\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/body\u003e\u003c/html\u003e\n"</content>
              <cc></cc>
              <media><url></url></media>
            </item>\n<item>
              <title>Listen: Stop ‘Whitesplaining’ to Communities in Need With Caroline Whistler</title>
              <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 09:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
              <guid>80044</guid>
              <content>"\u003c!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC \"-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN\" \"http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd\"\u003e\n\u003c?xml encoding=\"utf-8\" ?\u003e\u003chtml\u003e\u003cbody\u003e\u003cp style=\"text-align: center;\"\u003e\u003cimg loading=\"lazy\" class=\"alignnone size-full wp-image-1284\" src=\"https://sheventures.centsai.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/IMG_8707PNG.jpg\" alt=\"third sector capital CEO caroline whistler\" width=\"443\" height=\"248\"\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003ciframe loading=\"lazy\" style=\"border: none;\" src=\"//html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/18231551/height/90/theme/custom/thumbnail/yes/direction/backward/render-playlist/no/custom-color/39008a/\" width=\"100%\" height=\"90\" scrolling=\"no\" allowfullscreen=\"allowfullscreen\"\u003e\u003c/iframe\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eInspired by her lawyer grandfather, from a young age Caroline Whistler grappled with the question: What does it mean to serve others in a measurable and impactful way?\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eTo that end, Whistler cofounded San Francisco\u0026ndash;based nonprofit \u003c/span\u003eThird Sector Capital\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e \u0026mdash; a consulting firm that has deployed $800 million in government resources and $40 million of private funding to help 40 U.S. communities. Whistler advises governments, community organizations, and private funders on how to help the public sector measure the effectiveness of their social programs to truly impart change and racial equity across the United States.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eAfter college, Whistler received a Fulbright scholarship to study how nonprofits in Brazil scaled their public programs \u0026mdash; and that's when she began to effect change. Given her self-described \u0026ldquo;very white suburban upbringing,\u0026rdquo; Whistler learned that the best way to help was to \u003c/span\u003e\u003ci\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003elisten\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/i\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e \u0026mdash; to take a step back from academia and work in solidarity with the communities that knew the issues they faced better than an outsider.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eNamed as one of \u003c/span\u003e\u003ci\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eSan Francisco Business Times\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/i\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e \u0026ldquo;40 Under 40\u0026rdquo; in 2020, Whistler is working toward improved and equitable outcomes for Black Americans, as she believes that if we can tackle racism in the public sector, there will be enormous strides toward equity and opportunity in this country. \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/body\u003e\u003c/html\u003e\n"</content>
              <cc></cc>
              <media><url></url></media>
            </item>\n<item>
              <title>Pay Off Debt Quickly and Get to Know Your Credit Cards</title>
              <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 09:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
              <guid>80057</guid>
              <content>"\u003c!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC \"-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN\" \"http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd\"\u003e\n\u003c?xml encoding=\"utf-8\" ?\u003e\u003chtml\u003e\u003cbody\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eAre credit card statements containing holiday purchases still arriving? If so, now is a great time to accelerate upcoming debt payments and get to know your credit cards\u0026rsquo; costs and features better.\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eThere are many expenses associated with credit cards including annual, late, and over-the-limit fees, and fees for balance transfers. No expense is as costly, however, as the cost of making minimum payments. It can take more than a decade and over $9,000 in interest to pay off a $10,000 credit card with an 18 percent annual percentage rate (APR).\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eThere are two ways to avoid the credit card minimum payment trap:\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003col\u003e\u003cli\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e \u0026ldquo;Find\u0026rdquo; extra money to pay more than the minimum\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/li\u003e\n\u003cli\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e Pay at least twice the minimum (or more if you can).\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/li\u003e\n\u003c/ol\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eBelow are specific details:\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cb\u003e\u0026ldquo;Find\u0026rdquo; Money to Pay More Than the Minimum\u003c/b\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eAction steps will vary from person to person. \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cblockquote\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e\u003cstrong\u003eAuthor David Bach refers to small expenses that add up over time as \u0026ldquo;lattes\u0026rdquo; and everyone has their own.\u003c/strong\u003e \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/blockquote\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eExamples include eating out, buying expensive coffee, and lottery tickets. Fewer or less expensive \u0026ldquo;lattes\u0026rdquo; will free up money to pay off debt faster.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cb\u003ePay at Least Twice the Minimum Payment\u003c/b\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eMany minimum payments on credit cards are calculated as 3 percent of the outstanding balance. \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eDouble that payment to 6 percent of the balance (i.e., twice the required minimum payment) and you can save a substantial sum of both interest and repayment time.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eFor example: If you make minimum payments on a credit card with a $1,000 balance and an 18 percent APR will cost $684 in interest, it will take eight years to pay off. \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eDouble the minimum payment from 3 percent of the outstanding balance to 6 percent of the balance and the interest cost is reduced to $285 (a savings of $399!) and the debt is repaid in four years.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eTo fully understand features and terms of your credit card(s), carefully read their disclosures (aka the Schumer box) and/or information found on your billing statement. There, you will find information about the following:\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cb\u003eUnderstanding\u003c/b\u003e \u003cb\u003eAnnual Percentage Rate\u0026nbsp;\u003c/b\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eLenders must disclose all types of APRs including introductory \u0026ldquo;teaser\u0026rdquo; rates (e.g., 2.9 percent for six months), standard APRs, and penalty (default) APRs that are charged for specific infractions such as late payments.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cb\u003eKnow Your Fees\u003c/b\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eExamples include late fees, over-the-limit fees, and fees for cash advances and balance transfers. These fees are not included in APRs because only some credit card users pay them.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cb\u003eMind the Grace Period\u003c/b\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eThis is the time period, typically 20 to 25 days, between the posting date of a transaction and the payment due date. A grace period is available only to cardholders who paid the previous month\u0026rsquo;s balance in full and on time.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003ch2\u003e\u003cb\u003eCalculate Your Balance\u003c/b\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e\u0026nbsp;\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/h2\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eTwo common methods are \u0026ldquo;daily balance\u0026rdquo; and \u0026ldquo;average daily balance.\u0026rdquo; New purchases are generally included. With both methods, the sooner in a billing cycle a credit card is paid, the more days with a lower balance and the lower the daily or average daily balance on which interest is charged.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eOnce you know the details, make sure you\u0026rsquo;re using a credit card that\u0026rsquo;s right for you:\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\n\u003cul\u003e\u003cli style=\"font-weight: 400;\" aria-level=\"1\"\u003e\u003cb\u003eConvenience users\u003c/b\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e (i.e., those who always pay their bill in full and do not pay interest) should look for a long grace period, no annual fee, low fees, and a good rewards program.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/li\u003e\n\u003cli style=\"font-weight: 400;\" aria-level=\"1\"\u003e\u003cb\u003eRevolvers\u003c/b\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e who typically carry a balance forward should look for a low interest rate, no annual fee, low fees, and a long \u0026ldquo;teaser rate\u0026rdquo; if the balance can be repaid before the introductory rate ends.\u003c/span\u003e\u003c/li\u003e\n\u003c/ul\u003e\u003cp\u003e\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003eUse this \u003c/span\u003eworksheet\u003cspan style=\"font-weight: 400;\"\u003e to compare the costs and features of your current credit cards and others that might have more favorable terms \u0026mdash; and commit yourself to paying off your remaining balance today. \u003c/span\u003e\u003c/p\u003e\u003c/body\u003e\u003c/html\u003e\n"</content>
              <cc></cc>
              <media><url></url></media>
            </item>
      </channel>